Good morning. Please note that today's presentation contains forward-looking statements that are
subject to various risks and uncertainties. Please refer to Intel's most recent earnings
release and annual report in Form 10K and other filings with the SEC. For more information
on the risk factors that could cause actual results to defer materially from our expectations.
The company's company's company's company's company's company's company's company's
company's company's company's company's company's company's company's company's company's
company's company's company's company's company's company's company's company's company's company's
And we eat new 후 Chip innovations took flight. The world took notice of closed fantastical
feet all thanks to those chips making enterprise sweet bringing AI everywhere. That's what good
partners do. Intel's enterprise solutions for you. Please welcome Chief Commercial Officer
Christoph Shell.
APPLAUSE
Good morning, everyone.
Welcome to day two of Intervision 2024.
Great to see you all in the room.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
We talked yesterday a bit about AI for good,
and I have to do that again.
Did you see how slim I was in that AI movie?
It's awesome.
I think I'm going to send it to my wife.
It's the new me, OK?
I really like it.
It's awesome.
Today is all about you, our customers.
We are talking about AI everywhere, PC, Edge, Data Center, Cloud.
And we want to make this work for you.
We will unleash the power of AI today for you.
And we will do that with no better person than my supervisor.
Our chief geek, Pat Geltzinger.
Please welcome you on stage.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
OK.
OK, fun.
LAUGHTER
Oh, my.
Good morning.
Welcome to Vision 2024 and welcome to Arizona.
You know, as I like to call it, the Silicon Desert.
An Arizona has been a manufacturing hub for Intel.
For over 40 years we've been here.
And this is the center for not only at-scale manufacturing,
but some of the most advanced packaging research
literally on the planet today.
And we were here a few weeks ago.
I brought a friend along.
His name's President Biden, right?
And Secretary Romando.
And I'll say it was a proud moment to be on the West Law
on August the 22 when we signed the CHIPs Act into law.
It was a proud moment.
Yeah.
APPLAUSE
And it was a proud moment in Arizona on March 20th
when we had the first major releases of the CHIPs Act
coming to Intel for our Ocatiwa facility.
The largest investment in the semiconductor industry,
in history.
So thank you all for participating in that.
APPLAUSE
And as I think about the CHIPs Act,
I call it the most important industrial policy
since World War II.
And I just ask each one of you, what aspect of your life
is it becoming more digital?
Everything.
And everything digital runs on semiconductors, which
means the world is increasingly critical on what we do
on what Intel does.
And so will your companies.
So will your families.
So will every aspect.
And we're just seeing this accelerate
as the era of AI is driving this huge momentum.
And we call it AI everywhere.
And with that, we're evolving Intel in a fundamental way.
Intel Foundry, the systems foundry for the AI era,
and Intel products, the modular platforms for the AI era.
But let's spend just a moment on manufacturing.
This newly created Intel Foundry business,
the world's first and only systems foundry for the AI era.
And we're committed by the end of the decade
to be the world's number two foundry
on a fast growth trajectory for the future.
And manufacturing, of course, Intel products.
Customer zero, as I like to call it,
but also opening the doors of our manufacturing
for the first time ever to be the manufacturing
partner for companies across the industry.
And this idea of Intel products and Intel Foundry
an incredibly powerful combination.
And if you think about this period of time that we're in,
maybe the most intense period of innovation
that the technology industry has ever been part of.
And for somebody who's been in it for over 40 years,
that's a pretty profound statement.
40 years, hard to say.
I'm still young.
I still feel good.
Yeah.
And we'll spend the bulk of our time today
on modular systems for the AI era Intel products.
And I sort of looked at the prior decade.
That's sort of boring.
We made PCI Jan a little bit faster.
We made DDR, the next increment.
We kicked up the thermal envelope a little bit.
We added a few more cores.
And we said, OK, it's a good chip.
Boring.
AI is making everything exciting like we haven't seen.
In this period of time, a fundamental drive of computing,
the biggest change in technology since the internet.
And it's going to reshape every aspect of our business
and yours.
And I simply call it every company becomes an AI company.
And this becomes the driving force of this expanding
semiconductor tan from about $600 billion
to more than a trillion by the end of the decade.
And Intel is rooted in, how can we help?
How can we understand your needs?
And we believe you need technology infrastructure
that's scalable and flexible built on standard platforms.
That enables privacy and security, top notch data quality
and availability.
That gives you choice, competition, time-to-value,
open ecosystems, and helps you to bring new talent
to keep up with this incredible pace that you're in.
And fundamentally, you need tangible business outcomes.
That's why we're here.
We don't build technology for the fun of it.
It's lifting our businesses to new heights
through this power of AI.
And Intel's on a mission to bring AI everywhere.
And with that, making it more accessible for everyone
of you and your customers, your employers,
from the clients to the Edge and Data Center
to the Cloud and Networks.
And this will be the framework for today's discussion
and how we help enable AI for every aspect of your business.
So let's start by taking a look at the client.
And that powerful, as Andy Grove called it,
the ultimate Darwinian device that
enables AI at the fingertips of every one
of your customers and employee.
I like to think of the AI PC like the Centrino moment.
Now, when I say that, if you know what that means, OK,
thank you, humor me.
And I've been around for a while.
But we standardized Wi-Fi for several years
and it sort of went nowhere.
There's a few access points and so on.
And then we put it into a volume platform
that we drove into the industry and all of a sudden,
every coffee shop, every hotel, every office,
became wirelessly enabled.
It changed the platform.
It changed the use cases.
And this is exactly what we're doing with the AI PC.
We're Intel is driving this new platform evolution, the AI PC.
We're ramping core ultra rapidly.
And when we launched it in December,
we had great response from the industry.
Today, we've already shipped over 5 million units.
We're on track, you know, right, MJ?
On track, you know, to meet or beat our 40 million unit
goal this year, 100 plus million next year.
You know, we are underway.
We just launched the commercial versions in February of core
ultra.
You know, we're expanding our AI PC developer program.
Also, and now, IHVs and ISV programs to go with it.
500 plus AI models are now optimized for core ultra.
And of course, working with our OEM partners,
Dell, HP, Lenovo, our roadmap is strong,
off to a good start, but with lunar lake,
air lake, Panther Lake, the roadmap is strong.
And in particular, I'm quite excited about the next platform,
you know, where before competitors ship their first chips,
you know, we're launching our second, you know,
lunar lake 3XDI performance.
This little marble has over 100 platform tops, 45 NPU tops
alone.
And before others get started, we're
on to the second generation, the third generation's in fab,
because we're going to drive the AI PC category to every
fingertip of your users and your customers.
And just like with Wi-Fi, after you've started to use an AI PC,
you can't imagine not.
What do you mean?
You don't have a Wi-Fi connection?
What's the matter with you?
Get rid of this piece of trash.
You know, AI will be enabling every business critical worker,
automating, streamlining, collaborating, new insights.
And later in the keynote, we'll give you some examples
of those use cases.
And you need to capitalize on this opportunity.
You need to refresh.
You know, on things like office productivity alone,
almost a 50% improvement over a three-year-old PC.
And most of you have four and five-year-old PCs.
Time to upgrade, you know, battery life, new four-factor
security, Windows 10 end of life.
And all of these, the killer reason is the new AI use cases.
Microsoft Copilot, Adobe Developers, Zoom teams,
summarization, translation, contextualization.
Every application is going through an AI makeover.
And without Intel Core Ultra, you're going to miss out.
Simply put, time to refresh.
I was with a major CIO recently.
And they were like most companies.
They're typical boring, four-year refresh cycle.
You know, and through COVID, it sort of extended a little bit.
It's sort of five years.
And we started to go through the use cases
that he personally would start to take advantage of.
Next phone call, CIO, we need to start
planning our upgrade cycle now.
An upgrade cycle, 10,000 might take, you know,
12 to 15 months to drive an upgrade cycle.
Windows 10 ELO, ELO is roughly 18 months out.
My challenge to you, leave today, call your head of IT,
ask what your AI PC upgrade refresh policy is.
And if it's not underway yet, tell them to give you a plan.
And if you don't get a good answer, I'll call them for you.
So the next piece of bringing AI everywhere
is edge and enterprise.
And we see that, you know, the edge
is this conglomeration of lots of different platforms,
lots of different solutions.
But the killer app for the next generation of edges, AI,
right, and all of sudden video analytics,
taking advantage of these vast quantities of data
that at the edge and largely wasted today.
And Intel's been delivering edge platforms for many decades.
And now we're building on those open standard platform
investments, enabling you to bring these new analytical
processes, data, you know, harvesting to those platforms.
And I call it the three laws of the edge.
And we see this idea of AI edge becoming really important.
But should the AI happen in the cloud?
We're at the edge.
And I call it the three laws, the laws of economics,
the laws of physics, and the laws of the land.
You know, economics is simply too expensive
to bring your data back to the cloud,
it gives you better cost control.
You know, bandwidth is the most expensive resource,
you know, that you have.
And cloud is the most expensive compute
that you have in the fleet.
So the laws of economics, move it to the edge.
But second is the laws of the physics, as I like to say.
And how many of you have changed the speed of like this week?
You know, hey, you know, whether it's skill shortages,
quality, security, all of those things, you know,
what's the round trip requirement?
What's the user interface expectations
for instantaneous response?
Or how fast does the robotic arm need a response?
If it's 20 milliseconds, you can't 200 millisecond round
trip to the cloud.
The laws of physics draw you to the edge.
And you know, hey, we're pretty profound technologists,
but we ain't changing the speed of light.
But maybe the third is the most powerful, the laws of the land.
And we often need to keep data on prem for privacy,
regulatory security reasons.
And data laws have become increasingly
diverse and restrictive by regions across the world.
And you know, every nation has some form of GDPR, you know,
capabilities in this volume of data
to tap in at the edges, simply staggering.
You know, and again, I was with the CIO recently.
And he was describing the 100 plus companies
they operate in at all the different data privacy
and regulatory requirements.
The idea of bringing data back to the cloud?
No way was his response.
Couldn't even fathom the idea of moving data out of region
for these use cases.
So the three laws.
And as the edge becomes increasingly important,
it's going to become, we believe, the dominant AI workload
research indicates that by 2026, 50% of edge computing
deployments will involve machine learning and AI
compared to just 5% today, a killer use case.
Now, one of the things I've really become infatuated with
is we've studied these AI use cases.
It's all about unleashing your data.
And how does your, you know, this massive proprietary data
sets, how can we turn it loose, you know, for AI deployments?
And Rags, retrieval augmented generation, is like so cool.
It's sort of this perfect bridge between cool new LLMs
and the big data repositories that you have today.
And Rags becomes, I think, one of the most important workflows
for corporations to take advantage of their data
and generative AI, where I can take modern open source LLMs.
And, you know, maybe if you're really good,
you're updating and retraining those.
What do you think?
Maybe once a week, maybe once a month, how often
are you updating the LLMs, right, that you have?
But then you're combining it with real-time data
coming through your vector databases, your streaming,
unstructured databases as well.
And bringing both of those together in real time,
we think is extraordinarily powerful.
You know, when Rags as a database encodes domain-specific,
business-specific data, and then packages that together
for these complex queries into open standard LLMs
environments, provides better real-time data.
You know, combining this gives better business results.
And with the rise of Gen AI in the workplace,
how do you apply it to your business problems and challenges?
So, what do you think?
You know, me giving a speech or me giving you a demo?
Let's look at a demo and have Diana here help us.
I'm not happy.
Hey.
So, Diana, you know, can you help solve this problem?
How can I take big data farms and combine it
with modern LLMs?
Exactly.
Well, I think you kind of alluded to the answer.
But I mean, LLMs are really cool,
but they're not always the most up-to-date,
and they may not have access to the most relevant information,
like company proprietary data, for example.
And as I think you mentioned, you can actually
solve that by adding a Rags to your LLM.
So, let's take a look at this.
We actually have here, I've got two chat bots.
They're both running, LOMA2, the 70 billion parameter
LLM on Gaudi2.
But the left one's just a stock one.
The right one's got Rags added, running a Redis
vector database on Zian6 with performance cores
and MCR memory from micron.
OK.
We'll try a prompt or two and see what kind of response you have.
Show me something.
All right.
So, the first one I've already got here,
we're going to ask something that's going to be something
we're asking for very up-to-date information.
And we'll see how these two LLMs work on this.
OK.
They're both giving us some answers.
So, that's great.
And let's see.
We'll try to zoom in a little bit here.
So, this is a stock one.
You can see we're asking for this information.
I don't have specific information.
Yes.
Yeah, sort of sad.
It is a little sad.
It's not very helpful.
Yes, I have information.
I have information here.
Very, very current information.
That's what you want.
I mean, otherwise, what's the point?
Yeah, OK.
So, that's cool.
So, you got any others?
I do.
Let's try another one.
I'm going to do a little cut and paste here.
Spare my typing skills, which are not stellar.
So, this question, I think you'll be interested in.
This is TCO benefits of the Rags solution on Gowdy2 on Zian.
So, let's see what kind of response we get there.
OK.
Once again, it's giving us a bunch of words.
Yeah, sort of.
I'm not sure the words are helpful.
Yeah, sort of like one of my uncles.
Lots of words, not much information.
Pretty much, exactly.
Yeah, exactly.
That's a great, great analogy.
Yeah, so you can see we've got a lot of words.
It's not really giving us too much information.
It's kind of just sort of guessing at things.
Yeah.
Whereas over here, on the Rags solution,
we are getting very specific information.
We are actually getting some really nice numbers.
OK.
I love that.
That's better.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Crosherly good to see you.
Over H100.
OK.
Yeah.
I figured you'd like that.
So, good job.
So, yeah, very specific.
And the other thing is we're not just throwing numbers at you.
We are actually citing the sources.
OK.
We know where these numbers are.
Yeah, I'm sure you don't have to worry.
We're like making this up and who knows where it came from.
So, very, very great results there.
OK.
Maybe one more prompt for the people.
Yeah.
Try something.
Maybe not all of them are TCO hardware folks.
That's what I saw for.
There's probably some software people out there.
So, let's ask a software question.
Forecast data, AI software market revenue growth.
Let's see what we get for that.
Oh, I can already see the stock law,
the two is hidden in the, I don't have access to real-time data.
That seems to be a common remark there.
So, yes, no access.
We're throwing out some numbers here.
Variety of numbers.
So, we're just kind of, you know, we're trying to come up with something.
But who knows where those numbers came from and how accurate are.
Yeah, it sounds definitive, but it's wrong.
Yeah, but there's two definitive.
So, we got two definitive.
So, anyway.
But here we have a definitive number and the source.
So, something that you can feel much more confident about.
Okay.
I should try one more quick one here.
The thing that I thought was interesting about this is,
this is the original question.
If I change this just slightly to say,
information instead of data.
Now, I personally don't distinguish.
I could have said either one, right?
It's not like, it seems like the same question.
So, I ask essentially to me the same question.
And you can see as the information is coming down through here,
the Lama 2 is giving us essentially a different answer.
In this case, it's like,
Jimmy's just giving us one of the numbers.
It didn't give us two.
So, it's like, well, did it make the other one up before?
I mean, where did it get that from?
Where's this one?
If you can see, we're getting exactly the same.
Yeah.
Very cool.
So, better answers, more current, real time information.
But what about performance?
Oh, performance.
So, we've got some good news there too.
Up to 2.35, better performance on this,
because Xeon 6 and Redis solution compared to previous gen.
So, more users, more LLM's, the same platform.
Really good news there.
Excellent.
Well, Diana, like always, you're the best.
Thanks, Fatma.
Yes.
And, right, I mean, there's lots of things going on in the AI space,
right, you know, models and training and MOE.
But this idea of rag of combining your data in real time,
right, with the latest in the LLM work,
I think this is really powerful to unlock this asset that you have.
And this is really, you know, very broadening the exposure
of your confidential information,
building on what you already have, where your data already is,
and enabling it in new and profound ways.
But of course, this still is sort of complicated.
And as we think about that, you know, we've clearly seen that there's
interest in how we can move these standards forward,
standard management, no networking lock-in,
no new security issues, working with LLM's that, you know,
can run natively on Zian, but also with Gaudi 2 and 3 and Nvidia.
And now is the time to build open platforms for enterprise AI.
And we're working to address key requirements that include
how you efficiently deploy, utilizing existing infrastructure,
seamless integration with hardened enterprise software stacks
that you have today.
You know, the high degree of reliability,
availability, security, support issues.
But Intel's not the only one seeing those challenges as well.
And we have strong support from the companies that are listed here.
You know, and some of the big critical players who control so much
of your data infrastructure, SAP, IBM, Red Hat, you know,
VMware and more.
And based on the strong ecosystems of support, you know,
that we're seeing in the incredible response we're seeing
from the industry players, we'll soon be launching an open platform,
these reference designs and solutions that bringing us together
will allow us to build the blueprints, you know,
have the reference design available, demonstrate performance,
interoperability, trustworthiness, and, you know,
ensure effective benchmarking and certification of these solutions
as well, and providing open governance so that the entire
ecosystem is moving forward, you know, together.
And Intel is stepping up to provide access to this,
to deliver our blueprints into the marketplace,
but also make it easy.
And I like to think of Intel developer cloud as sort
of the easy button, right?
And hey, how can we spin up, you know, a gaudy cluster
and have zeyons available?
How can IDC be this fast path for test deploy
and, you know, solutioning work that you would do?
And we'll be delivering these blueprints,
these authored, you know, development environments,
and stay tuned, you know, at the open source summit next week
in North America, or in Seattle, we'll be rolling out
many of the next steps for this open platform
for enterprise AI.
And we see Raga such a huge enabler, this private data
that you haven't been able to monetize in your businesses
forever and combining it with LLMs.
What a powerful model.
And let's talk to somebody who's working every day
with customers to enable enterprise AI.
Please welcome and joining to the stage
Accenture's Chief AI Officer, Landwine.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
Land, so good for having you join us here as well.
You're having me here.
It's like one of the coolest titles, Chief AI Officer.
Yeah.
So excited to be here to meet so many AI visionaries
in one place. Thank you.
Yeah, very good.
So you work with customers across the industry
to develop their AI strategies, help them drive value
and growth, and what are the biggest challenges they're seeing?
Sure.
This is what I do every day with 1,000 Gen.A.I. projects
under the belt.
I have so many lessons to share.
1,000 Gen.A.I. products.
Wow.
But today, I will focus on three common challenges
to AI adoption.
One, ambiguous value realization.
OK.
Many clients are telling me it's really hard
to realize value from their AI investment.
And that's even with very well-defined AI KPIs, metrics,
things like that.
And oftentimes, that's because they are only
associating AI KPIs to the task level.
So having this kind of a task oriented task-centric approach,
you're missing out a lot of aggregate value
on the holistic level.
That's why in Accenture, we are a big proponent of, OK,
you really need to take an enterprise ring mentioned
approach by implementing AI across your entire workflow,
or in some cases, even disrupting your existing workflow.
The second challenge is insufficient data quality.
The O saying of garbageing, garbage out
cannot be more true in the age of engineering.
I mean, they have garbage data.
Yes.
And I can tell you this is one of the most common challenge
many client-faced for companies who
are using pre-built LLMs.
They don't trust the data coming from the public internet,
because that's a major source of hallucination.
For some progressive companies who
are also trying to fine tune or pre-train their own models,
they also are lacking confidence about their internal company
data.
So let me give you one example.
Since Accenture does so much work in context and AI.
One of my clients are telling me they actually
have 37 versions of standard operating procedure, which
is supposed to be.
37 standard.
One single version of it's true.
So the third challenge is widened talent gaps.
Many people think that there's an easy button, right?
You can just press a button.
Jenny, I will come out.
That's not the case.
Many organizations need talents to build AI,
operate AI, also manage AI.
And that's also not forget about a lot of business users
that you need to be training so that they
can do effective prompt engineering
to get very relevant data, very relevant response.
Cool.
So those three.
So what's your advice for our customers and audience here?
Yes, I have a lot of advice.
But Accenture, we try to simplify this into five imperatives.
I already talked about the top three.
Lee with value.
It's time to build your digital core with data foundation,
with AI foundation.
Three is, breed your talent gaps.
But let me give you two bonus ones.
The fourth one is actually, it's
time to fix your responsible AI solution.
So that's not be theoretical.
That's not just talk about responsible AI gaurials.
Now start implementing responsive AI
systematically using technology solution.
Last but not the least, it's not one and done.
It's all about continuous reinvention.
So take a very marginalized approach.
Be ready for a multi-year journey.
So for the audience in the room here,
are you ready to embark on such an exciting journey with me?
Yeah, very good.
And Juan, thank you so much for joining us,
the partnership with Accenture truly is fabulous.
And we work with you in so many domains,
and it really honors us to have somebody
who's the AI expert of Accenture here in the stage.
That's, thank you so much.
My pleasure.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
And the third on our journey is,
what we do in the data center and in the cloud.
And you know, Intel's been innovating in this area
for many years, PCIe, memories, thermal,
networking solutions.
We've been driving more into our core CPU platform,
new capabilities like AMX and driving standards
for big data, classical machine learning and inferencing.
And the Zeon innovation machine is not slowing down.
And we're going to cover a little bit of that today,
and we're seeing this very rapid evolution of AI workloads.
And even as accelerated computing has taken this primary role,
you know, Gaudi arc accelerator solution for that,
we're going to cover that in a little bit.
But let's start by looking a bit more closely
at the Zeon portfolio.
And I'm very happy to announce the next generation of Zeon,
Zeon six processors, the new brand for our next generation
of both Efficient Core and Performance Core solution, Zeon six.
And with the rapid rise in computing requirements,
and the immense data sets that we're working with,
workloads are driving trade-offs for performance,
efficiency, and density.
And in return, more demand for CPUs.
And cores that deliver better performance per watt.
And I'm happy to share that the next generation,
you know, is enabling for the first time
our Zeon six with E Core, uniquely addressing these challenges.
And this is based on Intel three, one of my five nodes per four years.
You know, so this is like, you know, poppies little baby here.
You know, one of our nodes here is we're coming into market.
And this is our first volume part on Intel three
that we'll be bringing into the marketplace.
And super excited, you know, it's coming along very well
and we'll be moving here farce into production.
This quarter, and we'll be working with our customers,
our OEMs to make that available.
And we're seeing this ability to deliver distinct advantages,
you know, for cloud native, you know,
for volume container solutions,
hyper scale workloads, and delivering up to 2.7X better
rack density, 2.5X performance per watt improvements.
And when you think about that,
how many of your data centers have excess power budget?
No, right?
And every watt, right, is a TCO challenge for you.
And you know, let's take an example of a telco server deployment,
you know, where they might have 200 racks
using second gen Zeon for their infrastructure
for their telco environment.
With Zeon 6 with E-Cores, we can reduce that down to just 72 racks,
same performance, same capabilities,
and less management, less networking, you know,
less things to upgrade, less things to be supporting the environment.
And this results in over one megawatts of power savings
in a traditional data center, or 1300 Arizona homes,
you know, now have energy sources available to them.
Zeon 6 platforms also provide up to 27% lower
embodied carbon footprint.
So we're driving down the amounts of carbon
and our supply chain as well.
You know, it's simply put, it frees up energy capacity,
builds TCO efficiency, improves physical space,
that enables our next generation, Gen AI,
and P-Core solutions into the marketplace.
Well, the big brother of Sierra Forest is our Zeon Gen 6 processor,
formerly known as granite rapids with P-Cores.
And of course, we have one of those wafers here too,
what a surprise.
And here's our granite rapids Intel 3 wafers,
which will be launching shortly after the Sierra Forest product.
And we're quite excited to be ramping this
into the marketplace this year, also on the Intel 3 process technology.
So it's sort of like twins, right?
Now, you know, I've touched on this idea of your data,
your data stack.
And almost every one of your data stacks runs on,
Zeon, right?
Yes, where the databases are running.
And amazingly, here we are in year 22 or so
of the cloud journey.
And the majority over 60% of computing is now done
in the cloud or in some cloud embodiments,
but the vast majority of data is still on-prem.
And indications are that 66% of that data is unused,
and 90% of the unstructured data is unused.
What a value unlock.
And this idea of LLMs and RAG gives us extraordinary opportunity
to unlock this hidden asset that you and your businesses
aren't being able to leverage and operate on today.
And Zeon is clearly a tremendous machine
for running these RAG environments and making LLMs
more effective and efficient on your data.
And Zeon is not only able to be your database front end,
but increasingly, it's able to run the LLMs as well.
No new management, no new networking,
no new security models, no new IT, things to learn,
no proprietary networking.
It just works on the industry standards, Zeon's
that you know and love.
And we're seeing some extraordinary steps
in the AI computing landscape, advances and algorithms
and new data types that make the AI infrastructure more
efficient.
Now, if some of this data type stuff,
I just find amazing.
So here I am.
I'm a young engineer, and I am helping
to establish IEEE P754.
How many of you know what that was?
That was the 64-bit IEEE floating point standard
that also included 80-bit mode capabilities
for maximum precision.
Anybody remember that stuff?
Yeah, I worked on that.
Man, that was like, precision was,
I couldn't believe some of those crazy rounding modes
and stuff.
And now we have 32-bit floating point,
and then BF16 for 16-bit, and then FPA, and now FP4.
It's like just guessing.
In these narrower formats, though,
are allowing memory compression, efficient training,
and inferencing with minimal accuracy loss.
And Intel is working closely to drive standards
in this space, in particular, the micro-scaling formats
or MX alliance, working with companies like ARM, Qualcomm,
and Nvidia to standardize the next generation data types
for both training and inferencing, enabling innovation,
advancements in the algorithms, enabling memory compression,
allowing lower cost and more efficient solutions.
And one such format is called MXFP4.
I know it just rolls off your tongue, practice it.
Or it's a floating point for bit standard,
for how you can have radix and mantissa operate effectively
in this environment without sacrificing accuracy.
And with that, let me introduce you
to the next star of the Gen AI show, the Zeon 6 PCOR
or Granite Rapids that we were looking over.
And what I want to show you here, so here's my Granite Rapids,
quite excited for this baby coming into the marketplace this year.
But let's get started by looking at four different tech streaming
services that are running on three generations of Zeon.
And over here, we have two generations of Gen 4,
we have Gen 5, and then Zeon 6 here.
And what we're going to do is we're going to take one common
LAMA 270B parameter and a pretty chunky model,
so a pretty big thing.
And in the first two systems, we're going to write a high coup
about Intel AI solutions.
And this one's going to be using FP16,
and this one's going to be using the four bit that we just described.
So let's kick these off, and we're going
to see the comparison of just moving to the four-bit format
on the same generation of hardware.
So we'll get this kicked off, write a high coup about Intel AI solutions.
OK, sure.
And quickly running through it, and we see over here 170 milliseconds
of latency and not quite done over here yet.
We're getting to it shortly here.
And what you'll see is about a 3X improvement in the latency
just as we move to the modern data types for the FP4.
Well, that's pretty good, don't you think?
Yeah, that's sort of for free.
APPLAUSE
OK, now let's go from Gen 4 to Gen 5.
And we're going to run the same query,
and we'll see how long it takes us on a Gen 5 machine.
And we'll have this guy run through here.
So here's a high coup about Intel AI software solutions.
And we're now at 150 milliseconds, or about a 3X reduction
as we went from Gen 4 to Gen 5.
What do you think?
Pretty good?
APPLAUSE
And that is really good.
But most would say 100 milliseconds is sort of the threshold.
So for a model size and query types,
so can we get below 100 milliseconds?
What do you think?
100 milliseconds?
Maybe.
Let's give it a try.
And we'll kick this baby off here.
If I hit the Enter versus the Shift key,
and over here we'll quickly see that's 82 milliseconds.
APPLAUSE
So literally across three generations of Zion,
taking advantage of our latest innovations on granite rapids,
monument creek memory, the highest performance DRAM memory,
combining that with FP4, a model, MXFP4 capabilities,
brings us clearly in range where I can now
run very hefty models right on the Zion platform.
From fourth Gen Zion with 16 bits up to today,
less than 100 milliseconds, 6.4 X improvement
from Gen 4 to Zion 6 on a 70 billion parameter model
and again, without major upgrades,
just run it in your data centers.
This is Lama 270B parameters, no expensive proprietary stuff,
crap, whatever, entering your data center,
unleashing the most dramatic source of business already available,
taking advantage of the data in your data center,
in your databases that's available today.
Now, that's really good.
But one of the other things that comes next to this
is we unleash the value of your data.
What's the security model?
What's the security profile associated with it?
And in an AI everywhere world, security
becomes even more important as we unleash your data sources.
We need to be able to confidently bring
zero trust environments to your fingertips.
And this is why Intel has been working aggressively
to build out confidential computing.
Where there's increasing concern for the stringent policies
that you have around data,
increasing regulatory environments that you see,
not just on data, but the EU AI Act
and the US executive order on safe and secure trust
where the AI.
And all of these things put more demands on the security model.
And that's why Intel TDX that we debuted
in our fourth Gen Zeon processors are now
available in Alibaba, Azure, Google, IBM Cloud.
And at various stages of coming to broad market availability.
And just this week, Google Cloud is announcing
the public preview of its next Gen confidential VM services
leveraging Intel TDX.
So now, how do I leverage my standard capabilities
and bring modern AI models and algorithms
in a trusted execution model?
And Intel is also enabling that with the Intel Trust
and attestation services so that you have independent attestations
of the security models, of the model training that's going on.
And we're enabling this across all members of the Zeon family.
And we're going to extend that to Gaudi later this year.
We're going to support extending that trust domain
into other accelerators like NVIDIA.
And with Panther Lake, our 25 client product bringing
it all the way to our edge and client offerings as well.
So truly a full end to end confidential computing environment.
And we hear more and more concerned for the training.
Who does control my model weights?
And who is keeping my data secure?
And how do I know it hasn't been tampered with?
And this idea of being able to extend the trust domain
and combine Rags with industry LLM capabilities,
we see great momentum and customer adoption
to this model in the industry.
I think this is a sweet spot for enterprise AI adoption.
But enterprises are also looking for cost-effective, high
performance, generative AI training
and inferencing environments as well.
And with that, we see them turning to models like Gaudi.
And Intel Gaudi's price performance advantages
lie in three fundamental domains, first choice.
People want an alternative, open software
approach and investments and providing time
to market available lower TCO solutions.
And Gaudi is the only benched market alternative
to the NVIDIA H100 for training LLMs.
And Gaudi AI, we expect that we're just gaining momentum.
And you're going to see today quite a number of customers
coming on board as we see the acceleration
of our Gaudi offerings in 24, 25, and beyond.
But one of the other critical things
that customers are saying is, boy, how do I stitch these together?
And with bringing Zian and Gaudi together,
it really is an AI system.
But then how do I scale those systems in my data centers?
And that's where the networking fabric comes to play.
And customers are asking for open technology-based ecosystem
for AI connectivity.
And while there's some proprietary solutions available,
we also see that the ultra ethernet consortium
and the work that we're driving is standing up to fill
this scale up and scale out networking domain.
And when I was a young engineer, working on the 286,
and the cube next to me were some of the engineers
working on the first ethernet solutions.
I thought networking was pretty stupid at the time,
processing was great.
But the venerable ethernet remains
the standard for how we do networking in the data center.
And through UEC, Intel is revolutionizing,
building on ethernet networking for AI fabrics
for the future.
And we'll be introducing an array of AI-optimized ethernet
solutions.
This lineup will include cutting edge AI
Nick cards that will be delivering, standard Nick solutions.
It will also include AI chiplets that
will enable for our customers and partners in Intel Foundry.
It will also include soft and hard IP
through Intel Foundry.
And it's building on and leveraging
the work that we've done integrating it fully
into our Gaudi solutions as well.
A range of soft and hard reference designs for AI connectivity,
because we don't need proprietary networking
for our AI solutions for the future.
What do you think?
Is that a winner?
APPLAUSE
Because we're out to transform large scale up
and scale out networking.
And being able to expand the sizes of these environments
and build AI systems that you need in your enterprise
without proprietary networking lock-ins in your environment.
We plan to deliver scalable reference designs,
integrating hardware and software capabilities,
reference designs that provide small models that fit
in a PC to medium and large models for enterprise and edge,
all the way up to big bulky ones for the cloud and API
access into other cloud services.
But ensuring security, openness, confidentiality,
and bringing your enterprise data to bear.
And we're going to work very closely
with our ecosystem of partners to make that available.
And enterprises are leveraging a range of industry solutions
to enable these cutting-edge environments.
And I want to bring up one of our friends,
one of our partners, who's helping us
enable this AI future.
So please join me in welcoming to the stage
the head of tech and business enablement
at SuperMicro Ray Pang.
MUSIC
You know, Ray, SuperMicro, been such a great partner for Intel.
You guys are so passionate about innovating.
I just love to hear from you about some of the innovation
journey we're doing together, starting all the way back
with Gen 1 of Gaudi.
Absolutely.
Thank you, Pat.
So SuperMicro embarked on the Gaudi journey
since the very beginning.
We developed an optimized AI server for Gaudi 1.
We continued with Gaudi 2.
And today, we are working hard to bring a Gaudi 3-based solution
to market.
So Pat, I'd also like to share some custom success.
SuperMicro deployed the largest Gaudi 1 cluster
in the world at the San Diego Supercomputer Center.
The Voyager Supercomputer, supported
by the National Science Foundation,
is designed to enable AI for science
and has been production for two years.
This is way before the chat GPT AI has this discussion.
It was before AI and HPC collided.
Right.
We were just building fast machines.
And with that, it's incredible.
And AI compute running on Intel Gaudi,
directly influencing science, research,
and the new breakthroughs there.
And other scientists, other activities
that we're working on?
Oh, absolutely.
So Pat, when you combine the power of Gaudi-based solution,
I'm putting in the hands of some of the smartest researchers
across the country.
Greetings can happen that benefit everyone,
including all of us in this room.
So it's really amazing.
I'd also would like to share the success we have with Gaudi, too.
As we stand here talking, a Zoom micro team
is working hard at the customer side.
Oh, which customer?
Oh, you can't talk.
The customer actually is in the audience.
If you want to stand up, I will mention your name.
Yeah.
OK.
They are shy.
They are Canadians.
You have to forgive them.
OK.
But in addition to big supercomputing,
Gaudi is also meeting the needs of enterprise customers as well.
We fish and scale out price performance as well.
Absolutely.
You're exactly right, Pat.
One of the biggest hurdles deploying large-scale AI infrastructure
is power.
Data centers around the world are literally running out of power.
So how do we solve that problem?
The answer is energy efficient green computing.
Green computing has been the DNA for Zoom micro since the inception
more than 30 years ago.
That's how long you have been knowing our CEO Charles Liang, right?
Yeah.
You guys have been passionate about green computing
since the very beginning of Super Micro.
Oh, absolutely.
When you combine energy efficient Gaudi
with Zoom micro's energy efficient servers,
customers can save not only upfront acquisition cost,
but also ongoing operating costs.
And you guys have some demos to show here
in the showcase as well.
Absolutely.
So Pat, we are showing a text to image generation
that will run in live on Gaudi, too.
We're actually running a phone computation.
Just see who can generate images the fastest
by typing the fastest.
I don't know about you, Pat.
I'm a slow typer.
For us to have a shot at winning, we have the cotton paste.
We're also showing a real Gaudi 3 system.
The world's first Gaudi 3 system.
You haven't even announced it yet.
We are a little bit ahead.
I encourage you, everybody to go to our booth.
Just check it out.
It's real.
It's not just on slide.
It's not just talk.
It's a real system in flash.
So Pat, I'm really excited about all the new approach.
You guys start talking about the system
at the data center level for AI.
At the Super Micro, we have
been expanding our global manufacturing footprint
to meet the rising demand from cloud service providers
and enterprise customers.
So today, we can deliver 5,000 fully integrated
racks per month, including 1,350 liquid coup d'racks.
So Pat, with the love sum of those racks,
I got the racks.
Time to go to scale.
So thank you for joining us today.
We're excited about the partnership.
And thank you for being here with our vision audience today.
Thank you.
Thank you, Ray.
We're being here.
Thank you.
We're seeing momentum like Ray was talking about.
So just driving customer deployments.
And inside Intel, I say, we have to be customer zero
for our own AI activities.
And we've been using different AI workloads
for quite a number of years.
Some of that traditional machine learning,
when applying meaningful and productive solutions
into our environments.
And I wanted to give you a glimpse
of some of those learnings here this morning.
Now, how many of you have bunny suited up
and been in a fab?
OK, a number of you had.
Well, guess what?
We're all going bunny-suiting right now.
So just down the road is our OcatiO facility.
And in it, we're going to go and see a live demonstration
of Gaudi's and AI PCs.
And we're going to walk into the fab right now
and show you the magic that happens behind the scenes
a little bit.
So with that, let's let me invite Rosary here.
And Rosary is literally bunny-suited up inside of the fab.
So here's our OcatiO campus just down the road.
And now we're moving into the fab.
And Rosary, can you hear me?
Hey, Pat, thanks for having me.
Yes, I can hear you.
Can you hear me?
Yes, you're coming through great.
And thank you.
And you know, Rosary, as I promised you,
I have just a few thousand of my closest friends here.
Right?
So don't worry about telling them anything confidential.
They're all personal and friendly.
So we're good, right?
As well.
Yeah, thanks.
Let me show you some of our latest AI innovations
transforming our manufacturing work.
Well, fantastic, Rosary, and Intel customer number one
for our Gen AI solutions.
So tell us more.
So here's one way we are using generative AI in the fab.
One of our goals is to keep our equipment up
and running all the time.
So when we have an incident on a fab equipment,
we want to find out if similar incidents have occurred
in the past so that we can understand the root cause
and resolve them.
And this is so that we can get the equipment back up quickly.
Fortunately, we have a huge amount of structured
and unstructured data spanning decades
and millions of records documenting our operations.
We can reference this massive body of data
to find a resolution to get the equipment back up.
However, this process is time consuming and can take hours
and sometimes even days.
Yeah, and this certainly isn't ideal.
Thousands, you know, we have fabs across the globe,
you know, thousands of different engineers
and equipment are running daily.
And growing worldwide.
Yeah.
But now we have a game changer.
We've started using LLM-based generative AI solutions
to enhance our productivity.
Let me show you.
So let's suppose you have an incident on some equipment.
You can come here and use natural language
to search for the incident.
So here I'm typing an example.
So on the right, you can see relevant past events
that are similar based on the semantic search performed.
And on the left, the AI assistant
has generated the most likely root cause
and resolution for the incident based on historical data.
You can also summarize the steps performed
to address a root cause.
So here you see the work orders that contain those steps.
And you can identify unique tasks.
And when appropriate, you can even launch a software agent
that can refine those tasks and take actions
to bring the equipment back up.
And then you can see the results.
You can see the results are in the software agent.
So we can see the results.
So this is a useful tool for us.
And so this is pretty easy to make actions
to bring the equipment back up.
Wow, this is pretty incredible, Roshri.
Literally a few clicks.
And you're getting decades of data
and being able to operationalize solutions.
This is incredible.
We can identify the root cause, resolution,
and even at times bring equipment back online,
using an LLM-based Gen-AI solution,
and our state-of-the-art factory automation software agent.
Well, thank you, Rajuri.
This is incredible.
And obviously, we're doing a whole lot of things
for equipment downtime, automation, improvement.
And this idea of, we're using the articulate software,
on-prem, secure, gaudy infrastructure for our solution.
And, you know, Gen- you know, articulate
been a partner company that we helped us start up.
And this is all inside of a proprietary,
multi-VPN environment.
I mean, this is the core of the core of Intel's operations.
So, you know, obviously, this never leaves our facility
under any circumstances whatsoever.
And now we're able to demonstrate
the most advanced Gen-AI capabilities in real time.
But one more thing, Rajuri, was that an AI PC?
I saw that you had there.
Yes.
This is the...
This is an AI PC, and let me show you something else.
So, with the Intel R graphics on this AI PC,
our image processing procedure is 1.5 to 2x faster
compared to previous technologies.
And up to 10x faster than CPU-only calculations.
In the past, obtaining high resolution images,
such as the ones that you see on the right,
that are used for finding the locations of defects on a die,
required additional processing on inspection tools
and could affect the throughput.
We solved this problem by training a cutting-edge,
super-resolution algorithm, and using the latest generation
of Intel processors for inferencing.
We can now process these images directly on our laptops
such as this AI PC and get detailed high resolution images
in under one second.
Well, hey, Rajuri, this is fabulous.
Those are great examples of AI is making life
so much easier, productive, and efficient.
Let's say thank you to Rajuri and her Octia Fab.
Applause
And these are real-world solutions.
We are transforming our manufacturing operations,
saving millions of dollars, accelerating our manufacturing
process, improving yields in our factories
and the productivity of our machines.
And I want to repeat what I said earlier,
time to upgrade your AI PC fleet now.
Because normally, remember, manufacturing, supply chains,
those kind of things, the developers get the cool PCs,
and then the mediocre ones go to the white collar workers
and then the crap ones.
OK, we'll give those to the manufacturing.
No!
Call your head of IT.
It is time for a PC AI refresh.
Because use cases like this show extraordinary value
for fleet upgrades now.
And the combination of Zeon, RAG, Gaudi,
extraordinary value in delivering these AI use cases
into your enterprise environment now.
Well, not far from the Octia factory
is another important place here in Arizona, right?
Maybe even more important in some regards.
Arizona State University.
Intel's biggest source of new engineering talent.
We have just under 5,000 ASU graduates
as part of the Intel workforce,
an incredible institution that's been transforming themselves.
And it is my pleasure to welcome to the stage
ASU President Michael Crow.
Thank you.
APPLAUSE
Good man.
I see you.
Very good to see you, Michael.
And, hey, sorry to miss you a couple of weeks ago.
I brought my friend, Podas, along.
Yes, I was very sad to be there.
Yeah.
You know, and, you know, I recently spent today talking
to some of, you know, all day
about the best and brightest minds in AI.
Maybe a few of them were ASU, you know, grads.
And they said, when it comes to AI,
we have a pretty good idea of what's going to happen
six months from now.
We have a vague idea of, you know, 12 months
and post two years, not a clue.
Right?
And what are you seeing from the faculty,
the research work that's going on with your teams around AI?
Yeah, well, Pat, what we see is that AI is this
monumental transformation moment.
We've got 1,000 faculty members already being trained
in AI systems.
We've got 100 development projects and more that are coming up.
This new technology that you're talking about here is unbelievably powerful
because it empowers the personal learner,
the personalized individual learning process.
And so what we see is that you're going to have AI operating
at every level, the level of the personal intelligent assistant
to the individual, the assistant to the teacher,
to the professor.
And so we're working on all of those dimensions.
We already have tens of thousands of users in our student body,
more than 100,000, basically.
So we're very excited and this is a monumental
transformational technology moment.
Yeah, it really is.
And this is like years out.
Yeah, this is right now.
Right.
Well, in fact, in fact, it's funny.
If you go on our Wi-Fi networks right now,
you'll see tens of thousands of people using AI systems
at the moment.
So people that keep talking about, well, this is down the road,
you're already asleep.
It's already a rocket ship.
And so it's already moving.
So let's talk a little bit about the pipelines of talent
for tomorrow and how you and ASU are making those possible.
Well, we've been working on changing.
We've gone from 900 engineering graduates just a few years ago
to 7,200 or so this year.
We're very excited about how we're doing that.
We found ways to defeat the barriers of calculus,
to defeat the barriers of chemistry and biology,
and to empower things using computational tools.
Not yet AI-driven as they will be.
So what we see is that we're going to see unbelievable talent
development trajectories, engineers with multiple majors,
people that dream about being engineering,
but maybe they didn't study calculus or math well enough
in high school.
They can get through that.
No problem.
And so what we see now is massive empowerment for talent
to move in any direction that they want to go.
Yeah, that really is stunning how you're able to, you know,
expand the potential workforce by using AI and helping them
over some of those blockers for them becoming engineers.
Well, AI is interesting.
It buys into our model as a technology of what we call
abundance versus deficits.
So most education systems in the country and around the world
are built on the deficit model.
What you don't know, you're too stupid to learn this,
you're no good, you're this, you're this, you're this.
And so we, AI, empowers the abundance of the individual human
beings' ability to learn.
So we see it as an unbelievable enabling machine to overcome
the limits of teaching, to overcome the limits of individual
humans being the only teachers.
And so we think that this is a huge enhancement.
Well, you know, we are so excited about the Intel ASU
partnership, how you're being one of the most innovative
driving forces in higher education in the America today.
We are honored to have Michael Crow join us on stage.
Thank you.
Thank you, Tom.
You know, and based on talented engineers at Intel
and across the industry, you know, we're seeing this growing
momentum of customer adoption and how do I enable AI for my
solution.
And with that, we're seeing more and more of them take an
advantage of the power of Gaudi to do so.
And our customers and partners are looking to deliver cutting
edge solutions to serve their customers in need.
And, you know, for instance, at Bosch, you know, they're doing
incredible work in this area.
And, Tanya, you made it.
Right?
Straight from Germany, please join me in welcoming Tanya Rickard
to the stage.
Yeah.
You know, hey, you know, you saw from our fab that we're pretty
excited about what we're doing and manufacturing and bringing
AI here.
It's such a pleasure to have you make it in, you know, for this
moment.
And tell us a little bit about your role at Bosch.
Yeah.
And in the morning, you told me maybe not everybody knows about Bosch.
Does everybody knows about Bosch?
Ah!
It's actually the leading technology provider in Europe.
And it's more than 400,000 associates, employees helping us
with nearly 100 billion turnover.
But it's more about the solutions.
We go from mobility, we go to industry, energy and building as
well as consumer.
And my role, I have also the honor to be on the board of
management, like you are your leading support.
And there I'm responsible for digital business and services as
well as our industry business and for the region.
You guess?
North America.
Very good.
So tell us about how Bosch is leveraging, you know, Gen AI and,
you know, we're taking this manufacturing engine to the next
level.
So at Bosch, AI is at the heart of our products as well as our
business processes.
At Bosch, we have all products contain AI, are engineered with
AI or manufactured with AI.
And we are looking continuously for partnerships and we are
very happy to partner now with Intel to go even faster.
We are developing since here we are commercializing
our products.
And we are developing, you might have used or for sure, your
fuse Bosch AI in your car.
Or when you go, I said mobility, industry, consumer and
buildings in your kitchen.
Do you have a connected open from Bosch?
Not yet.
No, yet.
Oh, it's a mistake.
Because it was an anonymous data from the baking and roasting.
What's this connected open does, Gen AI?
It recognizes a dish, what comes in, and it gives you a
recommendation on temperature as well as time for cooking.
But this is now, we want to go to manufacturing, right?
Yeah, very impressive.
Yeah.
And our products are manufactured with AI and what I have
seen is your products as well.
So there cannot be a better collaboration partnership to bring
manufacturing with AI, with Intel, Gaudi, processes,
on the next level.
So maybe we go in more detail, or do you want to add?
Yeah, you know, hey, you know, and I think some of the work that
we're mutually doing, right, you know, together to enable your
products, leverage our technologies, but also putting it to work
for our factories, your factories as well.
This is really incredible, Tonya.
And, you know, we just so appreciate you coming here to join us
on stage at Vision.
You know, thank you so much for sharing today.
Yeah, and I think, stay tuned.
What we will do together in manufacturing, it's about
optical inspection.
And there, you always don't know if there are not okay products.
And so, there are rare instances.
And together, we decided now that we will make sure that we have
more synthetic training data and with the synthetic training data,
you really have the chance to avoid this in the future.
And this is what I'm looking forward to.
Very good.
And this is the beginning of our journey.
Thank you very much, Tonya.
Thanks, everybody.
Thank you.
You know, Bosch, a venerable name.
But a growing pipeline of customers.
Another example, Nielsen IQ, consumer analytics leader taking advantage
of Gen AI with their discover platform, domain-specific large language models,
you know, running on a Gaudi and Zion.
Another example is Control S, one of the largest and fastest growing data center
and hosting providers in India and Asia.
And, boy, was I startled when I learned that India is very convinced they need
their own models for their environment.
And, you know, they're excited to train and be able to deliver that using
Gaudi clusters.
And, other example, like international flavors and favorite fragrances,
where they're innovating and molecules for perfumes.
Your next perfume could be Gen AI created.
And, you know, no customer, right, you know, example, you know,
with some of the leading minds in doing the research work of where AI is going
for the future.
And, an example of that is landing AI and Andrew Nying, one of the most well-known
minds in the area of AI research.
And, while Andrew couldn't be here himself today, let's hear the video message
and be able to share with us.
I'm thrilled to be here to discuss the transformative vision revolution
with large vision models.
The large language model, or LLM revolution, has transformed public process
text, and the large vision model, or LVM revolution, is just starting to change
public process images as well.
But, there's one important difference between LLMs and LVMs.
The internet text sounds similar enough to your proprietary text documents,
so an LLM trade on internet text can understand your documents.
But, all businesses have images that look nothing like internet images,
which is why you can do much better with an LVM large vision model
adapted to your particular domain.
Now, let me show you a quick demo of a pathology app using an LVM
trade-on pathology images.
We're training LVM for histopathology with over 200,000 unlabeled
images on the Galaxy 2 Intel DevCloud cluster.
Since LVM training is computer intensive, we scaled out to multiple
nodes. Thanks to the Intel DevCloud teamself, we're able to get on board it
to the Intel DevCloud and put our LVM training recipes to run on the Galaxy
2 cluster.
One thing we're running and scale out to work delight to the speed up.
Now, let's see this LVM in action.
Here, I have the LVM running on the Galaxy 2 machine on Intel DevCloud,
using this LVM as a foundation with fine-tuned it with just a few examples
to segment out the new Cliai.
As you can see, it does a great job.
But, the nice thing is that LVMs can do many different tasks.
You see the same LVM because it said fine-tuned it with some images of
liver cells to create a classification model that can detect the presence
or absence of cancer like this.
Your LVM acts as a pre-built template and in the midst of the need to construct
a new model from scratch every single time.
I look forward to seeing more enterprises unlock intelligence from the
image data and gain a competitive age in the market.
The future of large vision models is bright and it's nice to see it running
efficiently on the Intel DevCloud.
I love the work that they're doing applying AI and new domains like health care
and some of the research work moving beyond text and language models.
Another example customer, have you ever heard of Naver?
Just a few years ago, I had never heard of them.
And all of a sudden, I realized they're one of the fastest growing Asian
cloud service providers in the industry and a huge partner of Intel.
So let's hear from their CEO right now.
Hi, everyone. I'm Suyeon Tae, CEO of Naver.
Naver studied as a search engine in Korea.
We are now the number one Internet company in Korea with around 700 million
users across the globe.
Our global services include WebTune and Passmark in the US and Line in Japan.
Today, at Intel Vision 2024, I'm happy to share about Naver's partnership with Intel.
Naver was the third company globally to announce our own hyposcale Gen AI model.
And for this model to work with our services and ecosystem,
we must focus on R&D for powerful and cost-effective computing power.
That's why we are very much excited about working together with Intel.
I can wait to see what Naver and Intel can create for new AI chip environment.
And innovations, this will bring, please stay tuned.
And in fact, you don't have to stay tuned very long.
Let's bring on stage Dr. Ha, the head of research for Naver Cloud.
Thank you.
All right. So tell us how Intel and Naver are collaborating.
Na. Yes. Thank you for your question.
And I will see your suiyan mentioned.
Actually, the global sub-align R&M pioneer and the Korea's leading tech platform company,
Naver is a vision to develop and deploy a powerful innovative and safe sub-align multi-modal R&M.
Train with much more trust.
And so we decided to collaborate with Intel across three essential areas on Gaudi 2.
First, we established Naver Intel Core Lab to expand Gaudi sub-taire ecosystem.
In collaboration with many startups and the research labs in academia with our core app together.
Second, we plan to evaluate Gaudi 2 and look forward to the successful evaluation to establish on R&M training infrastructure on Gaudi 2.
Last, we expect to offer the commercial cloud instances of these R&M training infrastructure to global enterprises and public sectors for their competitive needs and innovations in U.
Gen A.
So, why did you choose Gaudi? Why us?
We already go to Ken's shop.
Indeed, it is the most promising and competitive option for R&M training and inference.
Naver confirmed the Gaudi's foundational capability in executing comfort operation for large-scale waters.
And with the Gaudi's AI-dedicated design, it is able to deliver the outstanding performance per watt and TCO.
Time-to-value is another key objective with the Intel Teams, the prompts and the responsive technical support.
This collaboration aims for the Naver to deliver the most powerful R&M on high-performance and cost-effective,
thus contributing to the vision of AI everywhere beyond our efforts for AI sovereignty.
Well, thank you so much and we look forward to many decades of great partnership with Naver.
Thank you.
The AI pipeline for Gaudi continues to grow and accelerate,
and a broadening amount of enterprise AI solutions, working with top OEMs like SuperMicro who we had here, HP and Lenovo.
But I'm most excited to talk to you about our next guest, Michael Dell, joining us right now.
Michael?
Hi Pat.
Hey, great to be with all of you. Thanks for having me.
Well, thank you, Michael.
You and I, we've been doing technology for quite a while now, and with that, it's just so marvelous to have you join us here at our vision event today.
Yeah, absolutely.
You know, we've been doing a lot of work with our customers for decades.
I think we might need some more fingers on the number of decades we've been doing this, but it's driven, you know, incredible outcomes.
We've had this build out of compute and storage and networking and all these advances in power and speed and automation and intelligence.
And now, you know, the software that's been built on top of that foundation.
And all that has really come together in this moment where we're kind of moving from computation and calculation into cognition.
And now we all have this sort of super genius cognitive capability right at our fingertips.
And every organization needs to reimagine their business given this superpower that's being unleashed.
Yeah, that's exactly right, Michael. And, you know, we're just seeing this across different industries and use cases and moving so rapidly.
And from your standpoint, where are enterprises on this journey? And what have you been hearing from your customers?
So with generative AI, enterprises are moving from pilot programs to production this year.
And what they want are the use cases inside their core processes that drive productivity and help them accelerate everything they're doing.
Software development, service and support, sales and marketing, content management, creation.
And you also showed some great examples in advanced manufacturing.
AI use cases are continuing to expand across all of large enterprises.
And the urgency for generative AI continues to grow.
And we're in this second year of the gen I phenomena with enterprises demanding more AI acceleration options to meet their infrastructure needs.
So maybe talk a little bit about how Intel and Dell are working together to satisfy those needs.
Sure thing. So we're working hard to meet the demand and make AI adoption really easy for these enterprise customers with everything they need.
And we're working on a complete AI system architecture with the servers, the storage, the networking specifically built for AI accelerated systems.
And also, of course, the AI ready PCs and workstations.
We also help them in the design implementation with our AI solutions and professional services.
And last year we launched our PowerEdge XE9680 and it has really set the standard for purpose built AI and generative AI compute with superior AI acceleration and diverse GPU options.
And overall, the market is demanding more choice for AI compute.
And we're working closely with your team at Intel to bring Gotti 3 to market.
Now, and we are super excited to be adding the Gaudi 3 AI accelerators to our PowerEdge XE9680 lineup this year.
Pat, your team has done a great job here. It's a great, it's a game changer.
Gaudi 3 strengthens our partnership by addressing customer infrastructure needs, reducing TCO and easing deployment.
And it's all through an open ecosystem featuring AI frameworks optimized for Dell and Gaudi 3 along with scalable Ethernet based AI fabrics.
And prior to Gaudi 3's release, we're going to launch the PowerEdge XE9680 with Intel's AI accelerators in the Intel Developer Cloud, which is going to allow select customers to test the Intel AI solutions on Dell hardware before implementation in their data centers.
Well, it sounds like incredibly good work that we're doing together, Michael. But before I let you go, anything else we can be doing for you?
Well, you know, we've always got a few requests, Pat. So, yeah, this is Michael.
It's been a lot of fun. It's been a lot of fun, you know, working super closely together.
Oh, well, something here just showed up. Working closely with your team to accelerate and look, what we need is more Gaudi 3 in volume. That would be great.
Well, Michael, I think the next shipment has arrived.
Wow, awesome. Cool. I'm going to go, I'm going to go far this up on our lab. Good to see you, Pat.
Well, I get that, I guess that call is over.
And, you know, it's only fair to show what Michael has been excited about.
You know, today, and maybe as we come to this point in the keynote, I'm excited to introduce the Intel Gaudi 3 AI accelerator for the first time.
So you ready? Intel Gaudi 3.
It's just that.
You know, huge advancements in generative AI, building on the proven performance of Gaudi 2, delivering 4x the AI compute with BF16, 2x with FP8, 2x the networking bandwidth, one of the half x.
The memory bandwidth for massive scale out, significant leap in performance for AI training, popular LLM's multi model support.
And Intel Gaudi 3 is architected from the ground up for efficient, large scale AI computing, supporting both scale up and scale out to configurations.
Gaudi 3 is great on benchmarks versus the H100 on top open LLM models, 50% faster in time the train, 50% better on inferencing, 40% better on inference, power efficiency, a scalable solution with Gaudi 3 using industry standard ethernet like we talked about before scaling performance from one socket to a 8x accelerator, UBB, a single node up to thousands of nodes and racks.
One of the key questions that our AI customers are asking us is, okay, how do I deploy? And nearly all of the Gen AI developments today are moving to higher level environments, PyTorch frameworks and other community models from hugging face.
The industry is quickly moving away from proprietary CUDA models, literally a few lines of code and you're able to be up and running with industry standard frameworks on power performance, efficient, Gaudi infrastructure.
Now let's talk a little bit more about availability in a bit nerdy or together. Intel Gaudi 3 is available to OEM starting this quarter of this year, three different industry standard form factors, the accelerator card that I was just showing off here to you.
We're also adding to the Gaudi family, a PCIe card, and finally our universal base board.
Look at this big boy. I always bring big brother along with me. And with it, that range of solutions, and here up to 14.6 FP8 peda-flops, greater than a terabyte of HBM3E, 192 native 200 gigabit ethernet connections in this big boy.
The first Gaudi PCIe card, extraordinary compute density, the same capabilities as the mezzanine card, giving our customers great flexibility, 1.8 peda-flops of FP8 capabilities, 128 gigabytes of memory in 600 watt TDP, making it an easy adjunct to a zon deployment, being able to deliver industry standard infrastructure into your data center.
And Gaudi 3 eliminates vendor lock-in with standard networking solutions in your data centers, in your cloud, and with open software environments.
Best of all, best of all, you're ready? Huge TCO advantages for your deployment. This is a winning solution. Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the Gaudi 3 generation.
And as you saw today, the momentum is building. The road map is strong. We're seeing this acceleration of high performance computing of AI workloads of Intel's eon and our next generation, Gaudi 3 solutions.
And if you look at the Gaudi 3 customers today, we see this growing momentum in the industry of our partners, our solutions, and customers who are now saying, man, this thing is great.
So let's put it all together for our discussion today. And let's bring Brian on stage, and we're going to show just an enterprise application or two here to finish up our time together this morning.
So Brian, you got to be thinking, good to show us. I got a couple things, fat. Okay. So first, you little while ago, you were telling our audience here all about LLMs, Chop Bods, Rags, and all that.
Let me bring this all together and show you a cool enterprise edge AI use case here that every single one of you here in the audience are going to relate to email.
Get hundreds of emails, especially to put on a show like vision. It's ridiculous. So how can I use artificial intelligence to get me through these things quicker? So.
Yeah, in box zero, the holy grail, the holy grail. I can never get to that. All right. So here we have outlook, a very familiar email email interface and our friends that iterate AI have developed this gen pilot service. And as soon as I click on it, I get a summary of what my customer wants. And that's just that a suggested response that's going to give me all the information specific to the cost to the product that the customer is asking about.
I didn't have to go through spec sheets, databases or any of that. All I need to do is hit compose right here and have a template ready to go. I can adjust maybe the pricing or whatever you know, but everything is right here ready to go in an email that everybody can relate just seconds. That's pretty impressive. Now.
So what else that's going to help with way in box, but we got a lot of other tasks. Yes, yes, we do. And you know, yesterday we actually recorded a podcast over here. So we could have used audacity not just to suppress the noise using AI, but also track separation, keep everything in their own track. You know, we could use that.
I've started to play with audacity on my PC. Well, how's it going? Yeah, well, you know, I have a face for radio and a voice. So we're working on it. We're working on it. Well, soon, AI will fix those things too. For those of you with film editing, right? We have AI effects with Filmora. And then we also have a few photographers here. I saw a couple of cameras earlier. Lightroom will help you with AI that can help you organize your photos. Maybe do some quick edits. And we'll do some quick editing.
And all that. Well, that's pretty good. So what else do you got? Okay, one more that I thought that was going to be kind of compelling for you in the audience here. Using AI locally on your system in real time. So maybe this looks a little familiar. The drawing on the left. Yeah, that's the Ohio facility. That's right. The Ohio facility. But I don't know why if we are here in sunny Phoenix, why do we have it in a rainy scenario? Let's change this to sunny and let's cue the prompt. And you'll see Pat in just.
And in seconds, this is going to come to life in a sunny environment with really very little to no effort on my part. And let's click it here. Here we go.
Okay. And like all the like all live demos. Let's see. Like all live demos. Okay. Well, now we have there we go. Oh, there we go. So again.
No, it's now that didn't take me billions of dollars and years to build that fab. That was pretty good. That was really good. And again, you know, it's not just about how cool this is. It's about the experience. I'm going to give to my customer. We just 10 extra seconds of effort.
AI helped me come up with a photo realistic render of the Ohio Fab the still under construction. Yeah. This is great Brian. You have me sold. All right. Well, you know, I know that we had some fun with this. You know, but again, the whole thing is about productivity. And I'm here to show the case for the demo guy.
Yesterday, I was looking for you, Pat, for the rehearsal. And they said that he was at a sporting event. So, you know, this, the whole thing was, okay, what if Pat was, well, no, what if I was with Pat? And then I came up with this. You know, I ran an LLM on my, on my system.
Yeah. That's what he came up with. So, okay, I think we're done. Yeah. Yeah, I think we are done. Can we get so many IPC's for the demo? Absolutely. Absolutely. Okay. Thank you, Brian.
Yeah.
Yeah, I would have loved to be helping the boiler makers last night, but my jump shot, you know, okay.
You know, everything I've talked about today, it's not going to happen overnight, but it's also not going to take long.
Yeah, we see this enterprise AI transformation, you know, happening right around us today, but we see it unfolding in three different stages.
First, the age of the AI copilot. And you saw that today. I got this like really smart thing, helping me do my job better.
You know, helping me automate streamline optimize my tasks. And we expect productivity improvements to maybe 25%, you know, from those kind of capabilities.
But the second age is die upon us. The age of agents where the AI automates entire workflows. And you know, think about this like an autonomous car.
I let go of the wheel and it's doing it for me. The age of AI agents is not upon us. And we expect that enterprises will develop the main specific models and agents will program to act autonomously, you know, through their periods and check out agents and compliance and customer service automatically partnering with us seven by 24.
And with this, you know, just being able to unlock next phases of productivity, but the third age.
The age of functions where agents start to interact with other agents and literally entire departments become AI automated solutions. And maybe we'll have the age of the first one person billion dollar company as we look to it.
But we need to be careful and be careful not to get stuck in the world's data. That's still held inside of these databases on prem. That's not being leveraged today.
And how do we, you know, bring this to every portion of our business operations as you saw. I need to transform my manufacturing in our fabs.
And we need to be able to get across the labor. We have to innovate them using AI to drive our fabs and manufacturing and each one of you need to do the same for your businesses as well.
Where the technology is gaining cognitive capabilities as strong as humans in different domains. And we expect that we need not a little bit more computing power, but 10,000 times more computing power for this generation.
And we're achieving full AGI capabilities, literally this decade. And as stewards of Moore's law, we're going to relentlessly pursue more power efficient computing.
Because all of this that we've talked about today, everything we've talked about is made possible by the power of silicon.
And we're going to start every company is going to become an AI company together will unleash the power of your data. We're going to accelerate your productivity.
We're going to enable your workforce. We're going to vastly improve the ROI of your technology investments, all while making it more sustainable and secure.
Intel, we were made for moments like this. Together with all of you, we're going to change the world again.
Thank you.
I'm feeling
I'm feeling good. It just gets that off. Don't want to miss it.